Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - Florida, [1870] - 1904 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0073
    Views in Florida: plants and scenery, including Spanish moss-covered trees, orange and lemon trees, including views of people picnicking under the oranges, and an African American man picking oranges, a large century plant, coconut palms; men shooting alligators, and with dead alligator, and an alligator on bank of river; homes; log cabins with shake roof, African Americans out front; two African American women on an ox drawn cart; African American men with cart drawn by three oxen; hotels, including an interior view of Tampa Bay Hotel Parlor; bathers at Palm Beach; river and swamp near Enterprise; plantation scenes on Ft. George Island, including old slave quarters, families in a field; Gainesville: general view, and African American man riding mule hitched to a cart; couple in a cart; the U.S. Coast Survey schooner Torrey at railroad landing, St. Marks; ruins of Fort Mantanzas.
  - Florida--Fernandina, 1865 - 1880 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0074
    Views made in the vicinity of Fernandina, Fla.: Calico Hill: men (including an African American) lounging at dock; people relaxing on porch; men under Spanish moss-draped oaks; view on the [St. Mary's] River; group of log buildings, cabins, with African Americans (plantation?); large house with balconies: "Rebel Col. Finnegans House"; interior view of a steamboat.
  - Florida--Indian River, [1880 - 1889] (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0075
    Indian River: a camp site; men on the banks of the river; a path through the hammack.
  - Florida--Jacksonville, [1870 - 1889] (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0076
    Jacksonville: from the south, man standing in boat in foreground; the National Hotel; "group of natives," African American boys sitting on barrels; "Aunt Dinah's," group of African Americans in front of small house with large oak next to it; "15th Amendment," two African American boys and ox cart.
  - Florida--Mandarin--Stowe residence, 1880 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0077
    Prof. and Mrs. Harriet Beecher Stowe's residence in Mandarin, including a view showing the family on the porch playing cards, working at needlework or holding a newspaper.
  - Florida--Oklawaha River, 1870 - 1892 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0078
    Views along the Oklawaha River: tourists on riverboats, including the Marion, Ocklawaha, Okahumkee, Okeehumpkee and the Putnam; swamps, trees, Spanish moss, and an alligator; Palatka: front of Putnam House, oranges at R.R. Reed's, African American man with ox, women in ox cart; soldiers standing by markers commemorating Maj. Dade and his men, massacred by Osceola.
  - Florida--Saint Augustine, 1865 - 1905 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0079
    St. Augustine: street views, including St. George's St. and the city gates; Charlotte St. showing buildings with balconies overhanging the street and African American workers; Treasury street, only seven feet wide; Rail-road Avenue; homes, including the oldest house in America, built in 1564, and a view of an arched colonnade in a home formerly used as a hospital; the waterfront, including general views showing the sea wall, and a view of the fish market; the Spanish or Catholic graveyard, showing tombs, and Father Varella's chapel; the Cathedral, including interior views; the Spanish convent, including an interior view with two nuns at prayer; the Episcopal Church; markets, including a building formerly used as a slave market; hotels, including the St. Augustine, and the Ponce de Leon, with interior view of the later; photographer's of the Florida Club, including Geo. Pierron in front of a studio advertising and displaying views; stereo inscribed by Geo. Pierron showing man (Geo. Pierron) sitting in front of large century plant; views of Fort Marion or Castillo de San Marcos: walls, batteries, gates, the moat and drawbridge, views inside the fort showing sightseers, soldiers, including Native American Indians, cannonballs and cannons, doorway with Spanish coat of arms above the door, a furnace for heating shot; the old Spanish fortified lighthouse, with photographer's gear in the foreground, and St. Augustine lighthouse, with distinctive striped paint; African American man on bench outside his house, "Uncle Jack, oldest inhabitant of St. Augustine"
    64 items
  - Florida--St. Johns River, 1866 - 1890 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0080
    Views along the St. Johns River: people, including African American mother and child in front of the Clifton Oak; a cabin at Magnolia, view entitled "Subject for Reconstruction"; views of Green Cove Springs, including the springs, sightseers, the landing and the hotel; views around Blue Springs, including views of the river, trees lining the spring; St. Johns River near Lake Harnly, alligator in the foreground; moss covered tree near Mandarin; a palm-thatched arbor or gazebo, books on the table, woman pouring something from a pitcher.
  - Georgia, [1860 - 1889] (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0081
    Georgia: group standing and seated near a palmetto tree, one woman wearing a Paisley-style shawl; scene during the laying of the Corner Stone of the Monument to the Confederate Dead in Augusta, April 26, 1875, showing the crowd, men in uniform, and a band on a platform; thatched cabin on Cumberland Island; African American women coming from the well, Wormsloe; African American men, women and children working picking cotton; African American man grinding an ax as girl looks on; African American man pulling plow, woman guiding it, rice field; African American men and women hoeing rice field; log cabins, African American families in front; young African American man playing fiddle-like stringed instrument outside a log cabin.
  - Georgia--Atlanta, 1864 - 1895 (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0082
    Atlanta: Street views, including one made before the destruction of the city, Nov. 1864, including covered wagons, soldiers in the street, commercial buildings; corner of Mitchell and Washington Sts. showing large buildings, with small one room cabins (slave quarters?) arrayed in front of it; later street view show advertising and street railway tracks; view looking along railroad tracks with bridge crossing above, another view from above the tracks looking toward car shed of Western and Atlantic Railroad; group of men and women picking cotton on a plantation outside Atlanta; night view of the Phoenix Wheel and buildings and fountains at the Cotton State Exposition; view of the exposition grounds, with plume of smoke from Hagenbeck's building on fire.
    10 items
  - Georgia--Bonaventure, [1870 - 1879] (Box 10)
    Identifier: PR-065-0083
    Views in Bonaventure, a plantation, later made into a cemetery: primarily views of spanish moss covered oak trees; Lamar monument; Paddleford monument.
  - Georgia--Savannah, [1860- 1885] (Box 11)
    Identifier: PR-065-0084
    Savannah: general and street views, including views of hotels, commercial buildings; squares and monuments, including the Pulaski Monument, Green Monument; the fountain in the park, surrounded by women and children; election scene, showing crowd listening to campaign speeches supporting Grant for President; the Exchange; a building advertising baths; waterfront, including view of moored ships, and African American men and bales of cotton on a dock; Independent Presbyterian church; view entitled "Uncle Abe's School house and scholars" showing African American man in top hat outside small cabin with four boys reading; studio portrait of Jack and Abby Landlord, Aged 100 and 110; boy on street with ox cart; African American man riding steer pulling cart laden with farm goods: view titled "Fourteenth Amendment, Bringing his crop to town"; African American woman and boy in front of small log house.
  - Hawaii, [1900-1910] (Box 11)
    Identifier: PR-065-0085
    Hawaii: train passing beneath palm tree; Judiciary building in Honolulu, with statue of King Kamehameha in front of it; Asian American woman and European American child in park among ferns and palms.
  - Idaho, 1872 - [1889] (Box 11)
    Identifier: PR-065-0086
    Idaho: Miner buying bread from "bakery" on horseback; miners relaxing outside log cabin, Coeur d'Alene; views at Sawtell's Ranch, Henry's Lake: interior view showing ranchers at right and left, and J.M. Coulter (botanist on 1872 Hayden expedition) and N. B. Langford (superintendent of Yellowstone National Park)
  - Illinois, 1865 - 1908 (Box 11)
    Identifier: PR-065-0087
    Illinois: ploughing on the prairie; group of children in a pony carriage, Evanston; Galena: Gen. Grant's residence before the war; Prof. J. A. Light's balloon ascension, Paris, Ill. Oct. 21, 1874; a home in Pekin; depot and arcade in Pullman; view in Springfield cemetery.
  - Illinois--Chicago, [1860] - 1908 (Box 11)
    Identifier: PR-065-0088
    Chicago: general views from Shot tower looking north west, from Waterworks looking east toward lake; from city hall looking north, northeast, northwest (showing Young Men's Association Library in foreground), west; northeast from courthouse; street views including Monroe Street east from Palmer House, with sign for Democratic Headquarters and pictures of Tilden and Hendricks on side of building; coaches on Grand Avenue; LaSalle St. north from Madison, and view of excavation of LaSalle St. tunnel; S.E. corner Clark and Randoph Sts., Clark from Washington St.; Michigan Ave. from breakwater, and from Adams St.; State St. south from Madison, two views, State St. from Adams, showing noonday crowds, trolleys advertisements and a clock; Wabash from Jackson St.; Washington St. River tunnel; Water St. from State; man and ox cart; parks: boaters and large gazebo in Central Park; boaters, gothic house and bridges in Jefferson Park; Lake front park from the breakwater; fountain and people, boaters and bridge in Lincoln Park; group relaxing in, and park factor in front of road house in South Park; people on rustic bench and fountain, and bear den in Union Park; monument in Rosehill Cemetery; exhibitions: C. B. Woodworth's exhibit of soaps and other goods at unidentified exhibit; botanical display, Chicago Exposition; interior view of exhibition showing winding path, plants and bridge over a body of water; views at Inter-State Exposition including interior views showing pumps, fountains and other goods; hotels: corridor leading to parlors, and dining room, Palmer House; Grand Pacific Hotel; Sherman House; Michigan Southern Railroad depot; Central Depot; office where correspondence is handled, and the mail shipping room at Sears, Roebuck & Co.; Western News company store interiors showing book displays; Booksellers Row, showing exterior of Western News Company; Dearborn Theatre; Board of Trade building; Chicago Tribune Building; First National Bank; City Hall; Customs House and Post Office, including view of post office after a fire, with building covered in ice; Court House under construction and view of n. side of court house square; interior view of the Chamber of Commerce; manufacturing department of A. H. Miller, Jewelry; Field Leiter & Co.; homes including Terrace Row on Michigan Ave., M. Ogden's, P. Schuttler's, J. R. Walsh's; 2nd Presbyterian Church, St. Paul's Church; Wabash Avenue Methodist Church; waterworks: tower at the West side waterworks; pumps at North side waterworks; Chicago River: looking west at open Rush, State and Clark Street Bridges; pedestrians and wagons waiting for Clark St. Bridge to close; general view of river from Randolph St. showing lumber waiting to be loaded; Randolph & Lake St. Bridges; group of grain elevators and Twelfth St. Bridge; loading a whale-back ship with grain; tugboat towing larger vessel; funeral procession for Pres. Garfield; procession of knights Templars; Stock yards, showing general view of cattle lots, hogs hanging in Armour's packing house.
    109 items
  - Illinois--Chicago--Fire, 1871 (Box 11-12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0089
    Views of the Chicago Fire, Oct. 1871: Mrs. O'Leary's cow; views of the destruction, including general views, views of building facades and walls, iron work, destroyed bridges, piles of rubble, interior views, man pouring water to cool off a safe, workers, men examining damage, a piece of the courthouse bell, a sign to Cash boys and work girls of Field and Leitner promising to pay what is due them, sign saying where business had moved.
    113 items
  - Illinois--Chicago--World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0090
    Views at the World's Colombian Exposition: Throngs of people at the opening, and view of the blind chaplain leading a prayer, and six hundred musicians rendering the Colombian March; general views, including views of the lagoon, the great fountain (one view on fourth of July with large U.S. flag in foreground), fireworks over the lagoon, and various buildings; buildings shown include: Administration building, Fine Arts building, German building; Government building, Horticultural Hall, Japanese pagoda, Liberal Arts building, Machinery Hall, state buildings, including the Illinois building, New York Building, Washington State Building, the Transportation building, Women's building; specific exhibits: children looking at the first locomotive, a modern speed-record-setting locomotive, the China exhibit, Japanese pottery in the Manuf. Building, German toy exhibit showing elaborate carriage filled with toys, center court in the Fine Arts building, Bohemian glass and stuffed animals including baby bison and polar bears in the Liberal Arts Building, women in the New South Wales exhibit, views in the Agriculture building including the Brazilian exhibit, and the goddess of the harvest in the North Dakota exhibit, interior views of horticultural hall including Florida's coconut tree, Oregon fruit, and a mammoth fern, general interior view and Pennsylvania coal in Mining Building, interior view of the California building, an Illinois farm scene made from grain in the Illinois building, views on the grounds: flowers on the Wooded Island, the Midway, including the Ferris wheel, a group of Javanese, Algerians with drums and instruments, the Algerian and Tunisian village, exterior of the Chinese village, "street life of Cairo," with men with donkeys and man on a camel, group of South Sea Islanders, one of McMonnies' horse statues, a statue of Christopher Columbus, the Peristyle, views on the lagoon including a Norse ship, Columbus's ships which are moored next to convent where Columbus founded an asylum, a bicycle club riding in the World's Fair dedication Parade; men looking on as water is poured on the burning Cold storage building; a group of ducks rounded up at the end of the fair; floral display in the shape of the world in Washington Park; a replica of the Nina.
    107 items
  - Indiana, [1870-1890] (Box 12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0091
    Indiana: J. C. Bridge's home, showing the veranda, Delphi; waterworks building, Indianapolis; the bones and tusks of the Lagrange mastodon; men dining at the Soldier's Home, Marion; view titled home in a log cabin", interior view made by a Pendleton, IN photographer (copy photo); men laying pipes for the Wolcottville water supply; Prof. J. Sams riding his high-wheeled bicycle through a pond or river, Wolcottville [see Collection file for letter regarding this view]
  - Iowa, 1868 - [1889] (Box 12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0092
    Iowa: Davenport: wreck of the draw of the railroad bridge after gale of March 17th, 1868, residence of John L. Davies, with family horse "Bob" in front; Des Moines: Congregational church, railroad depot, and looking north from the depot, with train in middle ground; studio portrait of a baby in a carriage De Witt, Iowa; view from the bluff opposite the seminary, Dubuque; views of snow bound train on the Milwaukee & St. Paul Railroad between Conover and Ridgway, after the storm of Jan. 7th and 8th, 1873; entrance to Burt's cave, near Maquoketa River, Jackson County with photographer's developing tent, center; north side of square, Knoxville, in snow; Newton school house with students in front; Courthouse, Sioux City.
  - Iowa--Muscatine, [1870 - 1879] (Box 12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0093
    General and street views of Muscatine, Iowa: one part of a five part panoramic view, showing river and part of the town; Iowa Avenue, with river beyond; views showing a main business street, including a bakery, confectionery, general store, the Star photograph gallery, a jeweler, hardware store, clocks on the street, and wagons and pedestrians; copy photo of group practicing archery, woman aiming at target.
  - Kansas, [1870] - 1907 (Box 12)
    Identifier: PR-065-0094
    Kansas: Light Battery 'K' at saber drill, Fort Riley; round-up on the Sherman ranch, Genesee; George Summer & Peter Walsh of Company L, 6th Cavalry, shot in front of dance hall, Hays city, by Comanches; Lawrence: girls Indian boarding school, street view shot from second floor of building showing wagon traffic and business signs, including one in the shape of a boot; family and cabin near Troy; riders at Wolf River Ford; corn fields of eastern Kansas.
  - Kansas--Leavenworth, [1870 - 1879] (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0095
    Leavenworth: approaching Leavenworth along the Missouri River, train and riverboat; general views, showing a church and other prominent buildings; street view with waiting wagons, drug store on corner; Courthouse.
  - Kansas; Missouri--Union Pacific Railroad--by Gardner, 1867 - 1868 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0096
    Views along the eastern division of the Union Pacific Railroad: State Line Hotel; Wyandotte: U.P.R.R. office, bridge building across the Kansas River; Lawrence: R.R. depot, Crandell House, looking up Kansas River toward Gen.. Dietzler's house, general view from Fort Union, State University on left, State University building, Fort Union, Gen. J. Lane's House; Leavenworth: R.R. depot, street view of Delaware Avenue, Catholic Cathedral, public school under construction; view from Moore's summit, showing corn field; men posed on stack of ties, with Gardner's wagon in middle ground, Tonganoxie; Perryville (Perry); rope ferry across the Kaw, Lecompoton; Topeka: state house under construction, first floor complete, R.R. depot, Kansas Avenue, Lincoln College; St. Mary's Mission, surrounded by picket fence; Potawatomie Indians at St. Mary's Mission; Lincoln Avenue, Wamego, with Alexander Gardner at right; general view of Manhattan, with Gardner in center foreground; R.R. bridge across the Republican River; R.R. depot, Junction City; Abilene: trestle bridge, prairie dog town; hotel and depot, Salina; ranch at clear Creek, formerly an overland stage station; hieroglyphic rock, Smoky Hill River; views in Saint Louis: Mississippi River, elevators, and a flatboat, Missouri Pacific Railroad depot, the office of the Missouri Pacific Railroad.
  - Kentucky, [1870] - 1909 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0097
    Kentucky: man sitting by waterfall, view entitled "Cave, upper glen"; men standing in road cut, near Cogar's; a covered "Mountain wagon"; men barbecuing pigs at G.A.R. encampment, Lexington, 1895; log cabin where Abraham Lincoln was born, Hodgensville; Steamboats on the Ohio at Covington.
  - Kentucky--Mammoth Caves--Proctor & O'Shaughnessey, 1866 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0098
    Views of Mammoth Caves made using Magnesium light: photographers and guides posing with equipment outside of cave, inside cave holding lantern and rock; a guide standing in "Scotchman's trap"; party dining in cave, including a cup of Bourbon; group dining in "Bandit Hall"; group on cliff above the "Dead Sea"; stalactites and stalagmites and other rock formations.
    31 items
  - Louisiana, 1871 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0099
    Men on an alligator hunt: holding guns and looking at alligator, two men in boat; African American man and woman picking cotton; view titled "Salt Mine Village" showing African American man in ox cart, two men on horseback, and two small houses on hill or levee above.
  - Louisiana--New Orleans, 1860 - 1902 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0100
    New Orleans: general and street views, including pedestrians, wagons, street railways, trolleys, one view showing a snowy street (possibly by B & G Moses, since the exterior of their studio is shown), a view showing a fire, with a steam pumper in action in front of F. Jaco[?] photo studio, a view showing Lilienthal's wagon, a Mardi Gras parade, with mounted participants, a fireman's parade, a group of soldiers riding in formation; businesses, including the Poydras St. (French) Market; Jackson square, with river beyond, and with St. Louis Cathedral; St. Patrick's Church; French cemetery; Parish prison and Tremé Market; St. Charles Hotel; Customs House; Weedsport skirt and Dress Co.'s exhibit, at Exhibition, 1884; views on the levee: riverboats and sailing vessels, including a view of a steamboat explosion, bales of cotton, and barrels of sugar, some being loaded, or moved to warehouses; Algiers ferry landing; view of a banana tree with bananas; a view of a three-story building labeled "Sheridan's H.Q." presumably in New Orleans.
    46 items
  - Maine, [1870 - 1889] (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0101
    Maine: group having a hay ride, wagon pulled by oxen; Water street in Augustra; train wreck on the Maine Central Railroad, near Bangor; group posing in front of a building (a church?) labeled "Biddeford Maine" and "No smoking allowed"; Lewiston: Bates College, and De Witt House; Limerick Academy; Durham Bridge, Lisbon Falls; Moosehead Lake: man sitting beside path to "Pebbly Beach", and looking down at Moosehead lake from Greenville; log being skidded up ramp, Temple Mill, Moscow; dam at foot of Oquossoc Lake; group on Paris Hill; Phillips: Barden House, Elmwood Brook; men on sailboat, and small steamboat on Sebec Lake; Skowhegan: train on railroad trestle, Coburn Hall; women in front of cook's cabin, Tim Pond; girl standing by road near Town House, Vienna; men digging train cut, possibly near Waldoboro; tree-lined street, Winthrop.
  - Maine--Bar Harbor/Mt. Desert (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0102
    Bar Harbor and Mt. Desert: Croquet party at Bar Harbor, tents in the background; large house or hotel, people on porch; Otter Creek from Green Mt., Mt. Desert.
  - Maine--Camden, 1865 - 1885 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0103
    Camden and vicinity: women and children picnicking; views of Megunticook turnpike, lake and mountain; Camden from Sherman's Point, men on a bench between trees, Sherman's Point.
  - Maine--Eads Falls, Naples, 1900 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0104
    Eads Falls; interior view of a store room; fish hatchery; covered bridge and several homes and other buildings.
  - Maine--Hunting, [1870] (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0105
    Views of hunting in Maine: E. M. Messenger and F. A. Aldrich, with their snowshoes, rifles, pelts and fish; several views of a moose hunt: men examining the kill, loading the game on a sled, back in camp, with game hanging up.
  - Maine--Kennebago Lake, [1880 - 1889] (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0106
    Kennebago Lake views: cabins and camps; boats along the edge of the lake.
  - Maine--Old Orchard Beach, [1870 - 1889] (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0107
    Old Orchard Beach: group on the beach, some in swimming costume; group on porch of St. Cloud Hotel; large group on porch; Old Orchard House.
  - Maine--Portland, [1865] - 1881 (Box 13)
    Identifier: PR-065-0108
    Portland, Maine: Broad St. looking down, with banks, ticket office and other commercial buildings; spectators of a sham fight shading themselves with umbrellas; the Observatory, church beyond.
  - Maryland, [1870-1879] (Box 13)